They were given 2 weeks. It lasted 6 days.
The Stanford Prison Experiment is a thriller, drama,
history film directed by Kyle Patrick Alvarez.
In 1971, Stanford's Professor Philip Zimbardo conducts a controversial psychology experiment in which college
students pretend to be either prisoners or guards, but the proceedings soon get out of hand.
Based on a true story.
Dr. Philip Zimbardo, played by Billy Crudup.
Christopher Archer, played by Michael Angarano.
Daniel Culp / Prisoner 8612, played by Ezra Miller.
Peter Mitchell / Prisoner 819, played by Tye Sheridan.
Dr. Christina Maslach, played by Olivia Thirlby.
Jesse Fletcher, played by Nelsan Ellis.
The Stanford Prison Experiment is a 2015 American docudrama psychological thriller film directed by Kyle Patrick Alvarez, written by Tim
Talbott, and starring Billy Crudup, Michael Angarano, Ezra Miller, Tye Sheridan, Keir Gilchrist, Olivia Thirlby, and Nelsan Ellis.
The plot concerns the 1971 Stanford prison experiment, conducted at Stanford University under the supervision of psychology
professor Philip Zimbardo, in which students played the role of either a prisoner or correctional officer.
The project was announced in 2002 and remained in development for twelve
years, with filming beginning on August 19, 2014, in Los Angeles.
The film was financed and produced by Sandbar Pictures and Abandon Pictures, and premiered at the 2015 Sundance
Film Festival on January 26, before beginning a limited theatrical release on July 17, 2015.
The film received positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of prison, experiment, 1970s,
based on true story, prison brutality.
The tone is dark and emotional and intense.